REMCO MOOIJ

in https://nl.linkedin.com/in/remcomooij

https://github.com/remco-mooij

Portfolio: https://remco-mooij.github.io/portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data Analyst with a versatile background in biotechnology and business management and a certificate in Data Analytics from the University of North Carolina. Experienced in working with large datasets and proficiency with a variety of software tools and programming languages. Blends education and experience in science, business and consulting with passion and skills in data analytics to effectively solve problems and demonstrate results.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

01/2020 - Present FINANCIAL COORDINATOR

Laurus Pariter Management Company

- Responsible for managing day-to-day financial activities of 7 franchises in the moving industry
- Successfully used Python and VBA to automate routine tasks
- Designed new tools to eliminate inefficiencies; advised and implemented new processes which led to increased productivity and improved transparency while minimizing human error

05/2019 - 12/2019 VISITING SCHOLAR | North Carolina State University

- Worked on a research project to study copper tolerance in monkeyflower plants
- Use laboratory techniques and software tools to identify specific genes of interest

02/2016 – 02/2017 **RESEARCH INTERN** | *Utrecht University* 09/2014 – 05/2015

- Worked on a large project concerning metabolic growth control in plants
- Accelerated this project by six months
- Developed an effective new method for researchers to study plant growth in the absence of light
- Performed research independently and effectively presented results in a group
- Conducted genetic and morphological analyses, GWAS, qPCR experiments and protoplast transformations

EDUCATION

05/2020 Certificate in Data Analytics | University of North Carolina

- 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills
- Classes in fundamental statistics, Python programming, front-end web visualization,
 MySQL & MongoDB databases, ETL, machine learning and other advanced topics

05/2018 Master of Science: Science and Business Management Utrecht University (Netherlands)

- Credentials evaluated for U.S. equivalency by WES
- <u>Finished courses:</u> Operations Management; Organization & Strategic Management; Economics; Marketing; Human Resource Management; Financial Management; Entrepreneurship; Molecular Plant Physiology and Biotechnology

07/2015 Bachelor of Science: Biotechnology

Inholland University of Applied Sciences (Netherlands)

- Credentials evaluated for U.S. equivalency by WES
- Followed courses in the fields of Chemistry, Genetics, Microbiology, Biotech,
- Data Analysis & Statistics, Bioinformatics

QUALIFICATIONS

Professional

- Strong analytical skills
- Great attention to detail
- Problem solver
- Strong interpersonal & communication skills
- Financial reporting skills
- Project management experience
- Scientific & lab research experience
- Sales & consulting skills

Technical

- Skilled in Python, SQL, NoSQL, ETL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and VBA
- Extensive knowledge of Pandas, Matplotlib, Flask, NumPy, API Interactions and web scraping tools
- Proficiency with D3.js,
 Plotly.js and Leaflet.js
- Knowledge of machine learning concepts
- Advanced Excel skills

Projects

Object Detection App

Web-based app that detects household goods and returns search results for those products. *Python, Flask, TensorFlow, Yolov3*. https://github.com/remco-mooij/Object-Detection-Project

Human Trafficking Stats

human trafficking statistics.

Python, JavaScript,

MongoDB.https://github.com/re
mco-mooij/human-trafficking

Dynamic website containing